# ANDRÉS MAURICIO TRIANA REINA

DATA SCIENCE
DATA ANALYTICS
SYSTEMS ENGINEERS
DATA VISUALITATIONS
FULL STACK DEVELOPER - DJANGO
MONITORING AND EVALUATION

+(57) 3108669185



andrestrianareina@outlook.com



@andresmtr



linkedin.com/in/andres-mauricio-triana-reina/



andrestrianareina.pythonanywhere.com

# **SKILLS AND TOOLS**

## OFFICE

EXCEL WORD POWER POINT

# **DATA COLLECTION**

GOOGLE FORMS
KOBOTOOLBOX

#### CODING

JUPYTER NOTEBOOK VISUAL STUDIO CODE GOOGLE COLABORATORY GIT - GITHUB

## **DATA SCIENCE, ANALYTICS AND VISUALIZATION**

PYTHON
PANDAS
NUMPY
SEABORN
MATPLOTLIB
SKLEARN
PLOTLY
CHART JS
SQL
DATA STUDIO
POWER BI
DASH - PLOTLY
BEAUTIFUL SOUP - WEB SCRAPING

# WEB DEVELOPMENT

HTML
CSS
BOOTSTRAP
JAVASCRIPT
PYTHON
DJANGO
SQL
GIT-GITHUB

## **PROJECT MANAGEMENT**

SLACK
TRELLO
MICROSOFT TEAMS

## **SOFT SKILLS**

PROBLEM SOLVING
CRITICAL THINKING
COMMUNICATION
TEAMWORK
CREATIVITY

# **LANGUAGES**

SPANISH - NATIVE ENGLISH - B2

# **PROFILE**

Data Analytics and Systems engineers with extensive experience in positions such as database management, data analytics, evaluation and monitoring, construction of management reports and progress indicators, using Python and different tools for extraction, debugging, analysis, visualization of data and information. Strengths in interpreting, analyzing and diagnosing process advances, good at designing and implementing operational plans oriented to timely decision-making

# **EXPERIENCE**

# (2021 - currently employed)

#### **IMMAP**

#### Data Analyst Expert

Compile, debug, process and analytic information from different sources, primary and secondary, using new technologies for processing and analysis of data, artificial intelligence, programming languages and data mining to improve the quality of information about products.

PYTHON DJANGO PANDAS WEBSCRAPING GIT-GITHUB KOBOTOOLBOX DATASTUDIO POWER BI EXCEL WORD

(2018 - 2021)

#### **IOM - INTERNATIONAL ORGANIZATION FOR MIGRATION**

#### Professional system information

Manage databases and update report indicators, guaranteeing quality and consistency of information, supporting consolidation of information for internal and external reports.

PYTHON KOBOTOOLBOX EXCEL WORD POWER POINT

(2017 - 2018)

## ASOCIACIÓN COLOMBIANA DE DISTRIBUIDORES PELÍCULAS CINEMATOGRÁFICAS

#### Manage databases - Cadbox

Manage databases of movie tickets sold in Colombia and update the information in the CADBOX app. In addition, manage users in the system and create reports for associates. **EXCEL SQL** 

(2013 - 2017)

## FUPAD/FUCOLDE

## Data analyst / Evaluation and monitoring

Manage, creation and depuration of databases with the purpose to build information, reports and indicators.

EXCEL WORD POWER POINT GOOGLE FORMS

# **EDUCATION**

(2017 - 2020)

# Systems engineer

UNAD - UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL ABIERTA Y A DISTANCIA.

(2014 - 2016)

## Technology in analysis and development of information systems

SENA - SERVICIO NACIONAL DE APRENDIZAJE

# **COURSES/CERTIFICATIONS**

Comprehensive SQL Bootcamp: Beginner to Advanced - Udemy SQL course - Sololearn
Interactive Python Dashboards with Plotly and Dash - Udemy

Python for Data Sciences and machine learning Bootcamp - Udemy
Big Data Analytics: Opportunities, Challenges and the future - Future Learn

Google Curso de introducción al desarrollo web: HTML y CSS - Google activate

Python course - Sololearn